Okay, if you've got it, great job.
좋아요, 이것을 해냈다면, 잘 했어요.
And if you didn't, good try and keep watching for the answer.
그렇지 않다면, 잘 시도했고 답을 찾기 위해 보세요.
All right, so here I am in Android Studio.
좋아요, 여기 Android Studio가 있고,
And I'm looking at the TextViews right now.
지금 TextView를 보고 있어요.
But I'm going to scroll up to look at the ImageView.
하지만 스크롤을 올려서 ImageView를 볼게요.
Okay, so a little bit about what I was talking about before.
좋아요, 제가 전에 말했던 것이죠.
If I put my cursor somewhere in this ImageView,
제가 ImageVIew 안의 어딘가에 제 커서를 두면
it's going to give me a blue box that shows me how big the ImageView is.
이 이미지 뷰가 얼마나 큰지 보여주는 파란 박스를 제게 제공합니다.
And it's pretty much the entire size of this phone screen.
이건 꽤 폰 전체의 사이즈죠.
Now I'm going to go ahead and add scaleType, and
이제 계속해서 scaleType을 추가하고
the two options that I'm looking at are center or centerCrop.
center나 centerCrop의 두 옵션을 추가할게요.
Now center doesn't actually scale the image,
center는 사실 이미지를 조절하는 것 같지 않네요.
it doesn't change the size of the image.
이미지의 크기가 변하지 않았어요.
So it makes it a pretty straightforward that I need to use centerCrop.
centerCrop을 사용해야 한다는 것을 꽤 확실하게 해주네요.
Okay, and you should see that the image now expands to fill the entire
좋아요, 이미지가 이미지 뷰 공간의 전체를 차지하기 위해
ImageView space.
확장되는 것을 볼 겁니다.
You might notice here that at the bottom there's a little white
여기서 이 아래에 이미지가 더 이상 확장하지 않는
If I go up here, which let's me choose between different devices, and
다른 기기를 선택하는 이곳으로 가서
I choose say a tablet like a Nexus 10,
Nexus 10 같은 태블릿을 선택할게요.
we can see that this image is not filling the entire space.
우리는 이미지가 전체 공간을 차지하지 않는 걸 볼 수 있죠.
Now this is bad because it means if you're viewing this on a tablet you're
여러분이 이것을 태블릿에서 보면 이 흰 공간이 둘러싸인
going to get this weird boxy image with this white space around it.
이상한 박스형 이미지를 얻는다는 것을 뜻하기 때문에, 나쁜 결과죠.
Although it might look fine on a phone.
폰에서 좋게 보인다고 해도 말입니다.
The reasoning for
이 현상이 발생하는 이유는
this is because I've put wrap_content instead of match_parent.
제가 match_parent 대신 wrap_content를 넣었기 때문입니다.
Let me change these to match_parent.
이것을 match_parent로 바꾸겠습니다.
Now when I change these to match_parent the image expands to fill
이제 이것을 match_parent로 바꾸면 이미지는 전체 뷰를
the entire view.
채우기 위해 확장됩니다.
So the point I am trying to make is that layout_width, layout_height, and
이것을 만드는 시점에 layout_width, layout_height,
scaleType all work together.
scaleType이 함께 작용하죠.
Let me draw you a picture to show you a little more detail about what I mean.
제가 뭘 말하는지 더 자세히 보여드리기 위해 그림을 하나 그려드리죠.
Okay, so let's say you are a bit curious about what's actually happening when we
네, 우리가 centerCrop을 사용할 때 실제로 무슨 일이 일어나는지
use centerCrop.
여러분이 궁금하다고 합시다.
If you go to the Android Developers website,
Android Developers 웹사이트에 가면
you will see that the documentation says the following.
다음과 같은 내용의 문서를 볼 것입니다.
centerCrop scales the image uniformly,
centerCrop이 이미지를 균일하게 조절한다는 것은
meaning that it maintains the image's aspect ratio.
이미지의 가로 세로 비를 유지한다는 뜻입니다.
And what this means is that it does this so that both dimensions, the width and
이것이 뜻하는 바는 모든 면, 이미지의 가로 세로가
the height of the image will be equal to or
대응하는 이미지 뷰의 치수와 같거나
larger than the corresponding dimension of the image view (minus padding).
그것보다 커진다는 것입니다(마이너스 패딩).
Okay, so one thing I can say about scaling uniformly,
좋아요, 제가 균일한 조절에 관해 말할 수 있는 것은
if you've ever tried to scale an image, scaling uniformly means that it
당신이 이미지를 조절[scale]할 때 균일하게 조절[scaling uniformly]하는 것은
keeps the image from getting stretched out either horizontally or vertically.
이미지가 수평으로나 수직으로 많이 늘어나는 것을 막는다는 것입니다.
So it does that scale, and then it makes the image large enough so
이건 조절해서 이미지를 가로 세로 모두 충분히 크게 했고
that both the width and height are going to be equal to or
이것은 대응하는 크기의 이미지와
larger than the corresponding dimensions of the image itself.
같아지거나 그 보다 더 큽니다.
Let's look at a picture.
사진 하나를 봅시다.
Okay, so here's your phone.
여기 여러분의 폰이 있어요.
And on our phone we have an image view.
폰에는 이미지 뷰가 하나 있죠.
Here's the picture for the image view, and
이미지 뷰를 위한 사진이 있고
here's the green box representing the actual size of the image view.
이미지 뷰의 실제 사이즈를 보여주는 초록 박스가 있어요.
What's centerCrop will do, will scale this image up so
centerCrop이 하는 것은 이 이미지를 크게 조절해
that without warping it, it fits in the box.
왜곡하지 않고 이 상자를 채우는 것입니다.
Okay, so without changing the dimensions I've scaled this image up to make it fit
좋아요, 비율을 바꾸지 않고 이 이미지가 초록 박스를 채우도록
in this green box here.
크기를 크게 했습니다.
Now because the image is this long rectangle,
이미지가 긴 직사각형이므로
it actually expands over the edge of the phone.
실제로 폰 너머로 확장되었죠.
centerCrop will center this image in the view, and
centerCrop은 이 이미지를 이 뷰 안에서 가운데 정렬하고
then as the name implies, it'll crop off the excess parts of the image.
이 이름이 암시하듯, 이미지의 넘어가는 부분은 잘라냅니다.
Okay, so I want to talk about one more problem that you might have run into.
좋아요, 당신이 마주칠 수 있는 다른 문제 하나에 대해 얘기하고 싶어요.
Views can overlap each other much like playing cards can overlap each other.
뷰들은 서로를 덮을 수 있어요. 게임용 카드가 서로를 덮듯이요.
And the order of these view tags here determines the order
이 뷰 태그의 순서는 화면에서 뷰가 위치되는
So since view A is first,
뷰 A가 첫 번째이므로
it would get placed on the screen first, followed by view B, and then view C.
이것은 화면에 처음 나타나고, 다음은 뷰 B, 다음은 뷰 C입니다.
Now because of the ordering that I put in this XML,
제가 이 XML에 넣은 순서 때문에
I can't really see my text very well in text view A.
텍스트 뷰 A 안의 텍스트를 잘 볼 수 없어요.
Let's try changing the XML and see how it rearranges my screen.
XML을 고쳐서 제 화면을 어떻게 재정렬하는지 봅시다.
Okay, so I've switched things around so now I have view B, A, C.
좋아요, 이것들을 뒤바꿔서 뷰 B, A, C를 갖게 되었어요.
This will then draw view B first.
이것은 뷰 B를 처음에 부릅니다.
Then it will draw view A.
다음엔 뷰 A가 오고,
I've just reordered the views.
이 뷰들을 재정렬했어요.
Everything is placed in the same position,
모든 것은 같은 위치에 놓여있어요.
but the ordering of how the views stack on top of each other has changed.
하지만 뷰들이 서로의 위에 어떻게 쌓이는지의 순서는 바뀌었죠.
And because of that, now I can see my text.
이것 때문에 저는 제 텍스트를 볼 수 있어요.
So you might have run into a similar problem with your card if
두 텍스트 뷰를 여기 놓고 이미지 뷰를 불러온다면
you put your two text views here and then you drew your image view.
당신 카드에서 이와 비슷한 문제를 마주할 수도 있어요.
Because it would draw your first text view, then your second text view, and
이것은 첫 뷰를 불러오고 다음으로 두 번째 뷰, 그리고
then the image, which takes up the whole screen, would have covered both of them.
화면 전체를 덮는 이미지를 불러오므로 그 모두를 덮어버립니다.
So just make sure that you got the ordering correct.
순서를 바르게 두도록 하세요.
Let's take a look at what that looks like in code.
코드에서 어떻게 보일지 보겠습니다.
Okay so here's my working code.
좋아요, 제가 작업하고 있는 코드입니다.
But I'm just going to show you what I mean by the ordering of views.
뷰의 순서를 정하는 것에 대해 제가 뜻한 바를 보여드릴게요.
Right now my ImageView is placed first, then my two TextViews.
제 이미지 뷰가 처음 위치했고, 다음으로 두 텍스트 뷰가 왔어요.
And we can see the text easily on the screen.
화면에서 텍스트 뷰를 쉽게 볼 수 있죠.
Now if I instead, cut this ImageView, I'm going to scroll down,
이제 대신 이미지 뷰를 잘라내 스크롤을 내려서
I'm going to past it right here.
여기 아래에 붙여넣을 거예요.
All right, and now I have TextView, TextView, ImageView.
좋아요, 이제 텍스트 뷰, 텍스트 뷰, 이미지 뷰가 있어요.
Well, it draws the "Happy Birthday,
이것은 "Happy Birthday, Ben!" 텍스트 뷰를 보여주고
And then it draws this Android party image over the other two TextViews.
그리고 이 Android 파티 이미지를 다른 두 텍스트 뷰 위에 보여주죠.
If I select the TextViews, I can see that they're still there,
텍스트 뷰들을 선택하면 그것들이 여전히 거기 있는 게 보여요.
they're just being covered up by the ImageView.
그들은 이미지 뷰에 의해 덮혀있는 것이죠.
All right, I'm going to switch it back.
좋아요, 다시 바꿔놓죠.
That's much better, my TextViews are on top now.
더 낫네요. 제 텍스트 뷰들이 위에 있어요.
Okay, and as we always do, let's go ahead and run this on our phone,
네, 우리가 항상 하듯, 진행하여 이것을 폰에서 실행해볼게요.
just to make sure that everything is working with the match_parents and
match_parent와 centerCrop에 관한 모든 것이 제대로 작동하는지
the centerCrop.
확인하기 위해서요.
Okay, awesome, this is looking pretty great.
네, 멋져요. 이건 꽤 훌륭하네요.
We have our image expanded to fill the entire view, we can see our text views.
이미지가 확장해 뷰 전채를 차지했고, 텍스트 뷰들도 볼 수 있어요.
There's one tiny little problem that we still need to fix, but great job so far.
우리가 고칠 작은 문제가 하나 있지만 지금까지 훌륭했습니다.
All right, you're doing a great job. Only one more attribute to change,
좋아요, 잘 하고 있었어요. 한 속성만 고치면 됩니다.
and then we're going to have our final birthday card.
그리고 우리의 최종 생일 카드를 갖겠죠.